Heungseok Park

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · VISUALIZATION EXPERT

SeongNam-si, Rep. of KOREA

"The purpose of visualization is insight, not pictures."

Pro**file**

Software Engineer of CLOVA in NAVER. Lead in projects designing and developing data visualization systems for various domains. Currently working on as a data visualization researcher/engineer for a Cloud-based Machine Learning Platform service at NAVER Corporation. Interested in the field of data visualization and machine learning.

Work Experience_

Clova AI Research, NAVER

SeongNam, S.Korea

Feb. 2018 - Now

VISUALIZATION ENGINEER & FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

- · Managed front-end parts of a machine learning platform including planning, design, and development.
- · Built various visual analytics systems for analyzing and optimizing machine learning models.
- Published various research papers related to machine learning platforms.
- Developed a Design system to reuse basic UI components within a consistent design theme.

3Secondz Daejeon, S.Korea

VISUALIZATION ENGINEER & FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

May. 2017 - Jan. 2018

· Developed data visualization modules, where users can review and analyze their past driving records comprehensively.

Education_

KAIST (Korea Advanced of Institute and Technology)

Daejeon, S.Korea

MASTER STUDENT IN GRADUATE SCHOOL OF CULTURE TECHNOLOGY

Mar. 2016 - Exp. Feb. 2018

- · Research Assistant of Social Computing Lab
- Advisor: Wonjae Lee

Ajou University

Suwon, S.Korea

BACHELOR OF DIGITAL MEDIA IN COLLEGE OF INFORMATION AND TECHNOLOGY

Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2016

- Academic Scholarships for 7 semesters, Cum laude
- · Advisor: Kyungwon Lee

University of Nevada, Las Vegas

Las Vegas, NV, U.S.

VISITING SCHOLAR IN HOWARD R. HUGHES COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING

Jan. 2015 - May. 2015

• Advisor: Si Jung Kim

Research & Publications

- Heungseok Park, Yoonsoo Nam, Ji-hoon Kim, and Jaegul Choo, "HyperTendril: Visual Analytics for User-Driven Hyperparameter Tuning of Deep Neural Networks", *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, In Proc. IEEE VIS 2020 (VAST, acceptance rate: 24.8%)*, [paper], [website], [video].
- **Heungseok Park**, Jinwoong Kim, Minkyu Kim, Ji-hoon Kim, Jaegul Choo, Jung-Woo Ha, and Nako Sung, "Visual HyperTuner: Visual Analytics for User-Driven Hyperparameter Tuning of Deep Neural Networks", *In Proc. MLSys 2019*, demonstration track [paper].
- Jinwoong Kim, Minkyu Kim, **Heungseok Park**, Ernar Kusdavletov, Dongjun Lee, Adrian Kim, Ji-Hoon Kim, Jung-Woo Ha, and Nako Sung, "CHOPT: Automated Hyperparameter Optimization Framework for Cloud-Based Machine Learning Platforms", *arXiv* [paper].
- Hanjoo Kim, Minkyu Kim, Dongjoo Seo, Jinwoong Kim, **Heungseok Park**, Soeun Park, Hyunwoo Jo, KyungHyun Kim, Youngil Yang, Youngkwan Kim, Nako Sung, and Jung-Woo Ha, "NSML: Meet the MLaaS platform with a real-world case study", *arXiv* [paper].
- Heungseok Park and Wonjae Lee, "What makes a Successful Course at MOOCs? The Effects of the Structural Positions in Review Networks on the Course's Popularity and Satisfaction", *Master thesis*, [paper].
- Heungseok Park, Hongjun Lim, Wonjae Lee, and Kyungwon Lee, "NetSet: A Systematic integration of visualization for analyzing set intersections with network", In *Proc. IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (PacificVis)*, Apr 2017 [paper] [video].
- Jee Jung Choi, Jungmin Kim, **Heungseok Park**, and Wonjae Lee, "Extracting Placeness from Social Media: an Ontology-Based System", In *Proc. IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining (ASONAM)*, Full paper, Aug 2017 [paper].
- Heungseok Park, Hongjun Lim, and Kyungwon Lee, "NetSet: Interactive Visualization for Analyzing Sets in Large Networks", *IEEE VIS Conference, Visualization in Data Science (VDS) Symposium*, Poster, Oct 2015 [poster].

October 3, 2022 Heungseok Park · Résumé

Patent.

International

• "Apparatus for Visualizing Analysis of Set Relationship in Complex Network and Method Therefor", Kyungwon Lee, Hongjun Lim, and **Heungseok**Park, International Patent Application PCT/KR2016/011868, Oct 2016 [document].

Domestic

- "Tuning Algorithm-Aware Visualization Method for Analyzing and Adjustment Hyperparameter Optimization Process of Machine Learning Models" **Heungseok Park** Ji-hoon Kim, and Jaegul Choo, *Korea Patent Pending*, in review, Nov. 2020 [document].
- "Apparatus and Method for Interactive Visualization for Analyzing Sets in Large Networks" Hongjun Lim, Kyungwon Lee, and **Heungseok Park**, *Korea Patent*, 10-1710606, Feb. 2017 [document].
- "Apparatus and Method for Interactive Visualization in Analyzing Multidimensional data in Complex Networks", **Heungseok Park**, *Korea Patent Pending*, 10-2016-0101233, Aug. 2016 [document].

Ser**vices**

Review IEEE Conference on Visual Analytics Science and Technology (VAST),

2020

Projects_

NSML: Naver Smart Machine Learning Platform

NAVER

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPMENT, DATA VISUALIZATION

Feb. 2018 - Now

- Managed front-end parts of a machine learning platform including planning, design, and development.
- Built various visual analytics systems for machine learning including model analysis, hyperparameter optimization, neural architecture search, active learning, and others.
- Published and presented various research papers related to machine learning platforms (DEVIEW 2018, SysML 2019, LINE Conference 2019, NAVER AI Colloquium 2019, IEEE VIS 2020).
- Developed a Design system to reuse basic UI components within a consistent design theme.
- Maintained the cloud service used by over 1,000 machine learning engineers and researchers

An Interactive Visualization System of car racing data for reviewing racers' past games.

3Secondz

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPMENT, DATA VISUALIZATION, WEB-DESIGN

May. 2017 - Jan. 2018

Dec. 2016 - May. 2017

- Front-end development, Interactive visualization, Web-design
- Live at [demo]

CommScope: An Interactive Visualization System of public opinions to 19th president candidates from Korean Online Community

Social Computing Lab, KAIST

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPMENT, DATA VISUALIZATION

• Front-end, Data analysis (text-mining), Interactive 3D network visualization, Web-design

Live at [demo]

Revolution

• Article at [Joonang Ilbo].

Development of Information Collection and Analysis Technique on Public Opinion related Future Energy Policy Institute of to Nuclear Energy based on Artificial Intelligent Big Data Kyung Hee University

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

• Twitter data crawling, data processing, network analysis & visualization

Oct. 2016 - Jun. 2017

Research on Cultivation Plan of Technology Manpower against the Fourth Industrial

NRF (National Research Foundation), Korea Polytechnics

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Oct. 2016 - Jan. 2017

 $\bullet \ \ \mathsf{MOOC}\ \mathsf{platform}\ \&\ \mathsf{online}\ \mathsf{review}\ \mathsf{community}\ \mathsf{data}\ \mathsf{crawling}, \mathsf{data}\ \mathsf{processing}, \mathsf{network}\ \mathsf{analysis}\ \&\ \mathsf{visualization}$

Analysis of public opinions related to city issues based on Online Social Big Data

Goyang City hall

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Mar. 2017 - Jun. 2017

• Twitter data crawling, data processing, network analysis & visualization

Ski**lls**.

Programming JavaScript, Typescript, React, Data Visualization (d3.js, three.js, deck.gl), Python, R, LaTeX

Tools Git, Adobe Illustrator, Premiere, XD, Phothoshop, Gephi, Processing

Languages Korean, English

OCTOBER 3, 2022 HEUNGSEOK PARK · RÉSUMÉ